http://www.peoplemeet.com/v3/privacypolicy

A People Media Site
Login Now
OUR COMMITMENT TO YOU
At PeopleMeet.com, your privacy is a top priority. Your privacy is at the core of the way we design and build
the services and products you know and love, so that you can fully trust them and focus on building meaningful
connections.
We appreciate that you put your trust in us when you provide us with your information and we do not take this lightly.
We do not compromise with your privacy. We design all of our products and services with your privacy
in mind. We involve experts from various fields, including legal, security, engineering, product design and others to
make sure that no decision is taken without respect for your privacy.
We strive to be transparent in the way we process your data. Because we use many of the same online
services you do, we know that insufficient information and overly complicated language are common issues in privacy
policies. We take the exact opposite approach: we have written our Privacy Policy and related documents in plain language.
We actually want you to read our policies and understand our privacy practices!
We work hard to keep your information secure. We have teams dedicated to keeping your data safe and
secure. We constantly update our security practices and invest in our security efforts to enhance the safety of your
information.
***
PRIVACY POLICY
Welcome to PeopleMeet.com's Privacy Policy. Thank you for taking the time to read it.
We appreciate that you trust us with your information and we intend to always keep that trust.
This starts with making sure you understand the information we collect, why we collect it, how it is used and
your choices regarding your information. This Policy describes our privacy practices in plain language, keeping
legal and technical jargon to a minimum.
This Privacy Policy applies beginning Jan 1, 2020. The previous version of this Privacy Policy, available
here, will apply until then.
FOR CALIFORNIA CONSUMERS
Please see our California Privacy Statement to learn about California privacy rights.
1.WHO WE ARE
If you live in the United States or Canada, the company that is responsible for your information under this Privacy Policy
(the "data controller") is:
People Media, Inc.
8750 N. Central Expressway, Suite 1400
Dallas, TX 75231
2.WHERE THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES
This Privacy Policy applies to websites, apps, events and other services operated by PeopleMeet.com.
For simplicity, we refer to all of these as our "services" in this Privacy Policy. To make it extra clear,
we've added links to this Privacy Policy on all applicable services.
Some services may require their own unique privacy policy. If a particular service has its own privacy policy,
then that policy -- not this Privacy Policy -- applies.
3.INFORMATION WE COLLECT
It goes without saying, we can't help you develop meaningful connections without some information about you,
such as basic profile details and the types of people you'd like to meet. We also collect information generated
as you use our services, for example access logs, as well as information from third parties, like when you
access our services through a social media account. If you want additional info, we go into more detail below.
Information you give us
You choose to give us certain information when using our services. This includes:
When you create an account, you provide us with at least your login credentials, as well as some basic
details necessary for the service to work, such as your gender and date of birth.
When you complete your profile, you can share with us additional information, such as details on your
personality, lifestyle, interests and other details about you, as well as content such as photos and videos.
To add certain content, like pictures or videos, you may allow us to access your camera or photo album.
Some of the information you choose to provide us may be considered "special" or "sensitive" in certain
jurisdictions, for example your racial or ethnic origins, sexual orientation and religious beliefs.
By choosing to provide this information, you consent to our processing of that information.
When you subscribe to a paid service or make a purchase directly from us (rather than through a platform
such as iOS or Android), you provide us or our payment service provider with information, such as your
debit or credit card number or other financial information.
When you participate in surveys or focus groups, you give us your insights into our products and services,
responses to our questions and testimonials.
When you choose to participate in our promotions, events or contests, we collect the information that you
use to register or enter.
If you contact our customer care team, we collect the information you give us during the interaction.
Sometimes, we monitor or record these interactions for training purposes and to ensure a high quality of
service.
If you ask us to communicate with or otherwise process information of other people (for example, if you ask
us to send an email on your behalf to one of your friends), we collect the information about others that
you give us in order to complete your request.
Of course, we also process your chats with other users as well as the content you publish, as part of the
operation of the services.
Information we receive from others
In addition to the information you provide us directly, we receive information about you from others, including:
Other Users
Other users may provide information about you as they use our services. For instance, we may collect information
about you from other users if they contact us about you.
Social Media
You may be able to use your social media login (such as Facebook Login) to create and log into your PeopleMeet.com account.
This saves you from having to remember yet another user name and password and allows you to share some information from your
social media account with us.
Other Partners
We may receive info about you from our partners, for instance when PeopleMeet.com accounts can be created through a partner's websites
(in which case they pass along registration information to us) or where PeopleMeet.com ads are published on a partner's websites and
platforms (in which case they may pass along details on a campaign's success).
Information collected when you use our services
When you use our services, we collect information about which features you've used, how you've used them and the devices you use to access
our services. See below for more details:
Usage Information
We collect information about your activity on our services, for instance how you use them (e.g., date and time you logged in,
features you've been using, searches, clicks and pages which have been shown to you, referring webpage address, advertising that you click on)
and how you interact with other users (e.g., users you connect and interact with, time and date of your exchanges,
number of messages you send and receive).
Device Information
We collect information from and about the device(s) you use to access our services, including:
hardware and software information such as IP address, device ID and type, device-specific and apps settings and characteristics,
app crashes, advertising IDs (such as Google's AAID and Apple's IDFA, both of which are randomly generated numbers that you can
reset by going into your device' settings), browser type, version and language, operating system, time zones, identifiers associated
with cookies or other technologies that may uniquely identify your device or browser (e.g., IMEI/UDID and MAC address);
information on your wireless and mobile network connection, like your service provider and signal strength;
information on device sensors such as accelerometers, gyroscopes and compasses.
Other information with your consent
If you give us permission, we can collect your precise geolocation (latitude and longitude) through various means, depending on the service
and device you're using, including GPS, Bluetooth or Wi-Fi connections.
The collection of your geolocation may occur in the background even
when you aren't using the services if the permission you gave us expressly permits such collection.
If you decline permission for us to collect
your geolocation, we will not collect it.
Similarly, if you consent, we may collect your photos and videos (for instance, if you want to publish a photo, video or streaming on the services).
4.COOKIES AND OTHER SIMILAR DATA COLLECTION TECHNOLOGIES
We use and may allow others to use cookies and similar technologies (e.g., web beacons, pixels) to recognize you
and/or your device(s). You may read our Cookie Policy for more information on why we use them
(such as authenticating you, remembering your preferences and settings, analyzing site traffic and trends,
delivering and measuring the effectiveness of advertising campaigns, allowing you to use social features)
and how you can better control their use, through your browser settings and other tools.
Some web browsers (including Safari, Internet Explorer, Firefox and Chrome) have a "Do Not Track" ("DNT") feature
that tells a website that a user does not want to have his or her online activity tracked.
If a website that
responds to a DNT signal receives a DNT signal, the browser can block that website from collecting certain
information about the browser's user.
Not all browsers offer a DNT option and DNT signals are not yet uniform.
For this reason, many businesses, including PeopleMeet.com, do not currently respond to DNT signals.
5.HOW WE USE INFORMATION
The main reason we use your information is to deliver and improve our services.
Additionally, we use your info
to help keep you safe and to provide you with advertising that may be of interest to you.
Read on for a more
detailed explanation of the various reasons we use your information, together with practical examples.
To administer your account and provide our services to you
Create and manage your account
Provide you with customer support and respond to your requests
Complete your transactions
Communicate with you about our services, including order management and billing
To help you connect with other users
Analyze your profile and that of other users to recommend meaningful connections
Show users' profiles to one another
To ensure a consistent experience across your devices
Link the various devices you use so that you can enjoy a consistent experience of our services on all of them.
We do this by linking devices and browser data, such as when you log into your account on different devices or
by using partial or full IP address, browser version and similar data about your devices to help identify
and link them.
To serve you relevant offers and ads
Administer sweepstakes, contests, discounts or other offers
Develop, display and track content and advertising tailored to your interests on our services and other sites
Communicate with you by email, phone, social media or mobile device about products or services that
we think may interest you
To improve our services and develop new ones
Administer focus groups and surveys
Conduct research and analysis of users' behavior to improve our services and content (for instance,
we may decide to change the look and feel or even substantially modify a given feature based on users'
behavior)
Develop new features and services (for example, we may decide to build a new interests-based feature
further to requests received from users).
To prevent, detect and fight fraud or other illegal or unauthorized activities
Address ongoing or alleged misbehavior on and off-platform
Perform data analysis to better understand and design countermeasures against these activities
Retain data related to fraudulent activities to prevent against recurrences
To ensure legal compliance
Comply with legal requirements
Assist law enforcement
Enforce or exercise our rights, for example our Terms
To process your information as described above, we rely on the following legal bases:
Provide our service to you: Most of the time, the reason we process your
information is to perform the contract that you have with us. For instance, as you go about using our
service to build meaningful connections, we use your information to maintain your account and your profile,
to make it viewable to other users and recommend other users to you.
Legitimate interests: We may use your information where we have legitimate
interests to do so. For instance, we analyze users' behavior on our services to continuously improve our
offerings, we suggest offers we think might interest you, and we process information for administrative,
fraud detection and other legal purposes.
Consent: From time to time, we may ask for your consent to use your
information for certain specific reasons. You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us
at the address provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.
6.HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION
Since our goal is to help you make meaningful connections, the main sharing of users' information is, of course,
with other users. We also share some users' information with service providers and partners who assist us in
operating the services, with other Match Group companies and, in some cases, legal authorities. Read on for
more details about how your information is shared with others.
With other users
You share information with other users when you voluntarily disclose information on the service
(including your public profile). Please be careful with your information and make sure that the
content you share is stuff that you're comfortable being publically viewable since neither you
nor we can control what others do with your information once you share it.
If you choose to limit the audience for all or part of your profile or for certain content or
information about you, then it will be visible according to your settings.
With our service providers and partners
We use third parties to help us operate and improve our services.
These third parties assist us
with various tasks, including data hosting and maintenance, analytics, customer care, marketing,
advertising, payment processing and security operations.
We may also share information with partners who distribute and assist us in advertising our services.
For instance, we may share limited information on you in hashed, non-human readable form to advertising
partners.
We follow a strict vetting process prior to engaging any service provider or working with any partner.
All of our service providers and partners must agree to strict confidentiality obligations.
With other Match Group businesses
PeopleMeet.com is part of the Match Group family of businesses which, as of the date of this
Privacy Policy, includes websites and apps such as Tinder, OkCupid, Plenty of Fish, Match, Meetic,
BlackPeopleMeet, LoveScout24, OurTime, Pairs, ParPerfeito, and Twoo (for more details,
click here).
We share your information with other Match Group companies to benefit you in two respects:
for other Match Group companies to assist us in processing your information, as service providers,
upon our instructions and on our behalf. Assistance provided by other Match Group companies may
include technical processing operations, such as data hosting and maintenance, customer care,
marketing and targeted advertising, finance and accounting assistance, better understanding how
our service is used and users' behavior to improve our service, securing our data and systems and
fighting against spam, abuse, fraud, infringement and other wrongdoings.
In order to improve your chances at building significant connections with others, we may make you visible on
other Match Group services or allow you to benefit from cross-platform functionalities.
We will of course comply
with applicable law and, where relevant, notify you of any such opportunity and allow you to agree or to refuse.
Examples of such opportunities may include the creation of a new service within Match Group, addressing a specific
demographic that we feel would be interesting to you based on your search criteria.
We may also share information with other Match Group companies for legitimate business purposes such as
corporate audit, analysis and consolidated reporting as well as compliance with applicable laws.
We may also share user information with other Match Group companies to remove users who violate our
terms of service, or have been reported for criminal activity and/or bad behavior. In some instances,
we may remove that user from all platforms.
For corporate transactions
We may transfer your information if we are involved, whether in whole or in part, in a merger, sale,
acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of
ownership or control.
When required by law
We may disclose your information if reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with a legal process, such
as a court order, subpoena or search warrant, government / law enforcement investigation or other
legal requirements; (ii) to assist in the prevention or detection of crime (subject in each case to
applicable law); or (iii) to protect the safety of any person.
To enforce legal rights
We may also share information: (i) if disclosure would mitigate our liability in an actual or
threatened lawsuit; (ii) as necessary to protect our legal rights and legal rights of our users,
business partners or other interested parties; (iii) to enforce our agreements with you; and
(iv) to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or
other wrongdoing.
With your consent or at your request
We may ask for your consent to share your information with third parties. In any such case, we
will make it clear why we want to share the information.
We may use and share non-personal information (meaning information that, by itself, does not identify who you
are such as device information, general demographics, general behavioral data, geolocation in de-identified
form), as well as personal information in hashed, non-human readable form, under any of the above
circumstances.
We may also share this information with other Match Group companies and third parties
(notably advertisers) to develop and deliver targeted advertising on our services and on websites or
applications of third parties, and to analyze and report on advertising you see. We may combine this
information with additional non-personal information or personal information in hashed, non-human
readable form collected from other sources. More information on our use of cookies and similar
technologies can be found in our Cookie Policy.
7.CROSS-BORDER DATA TRANSFERS
Sharing of information laid out in Section 6 sometimes involves cross-border data transfers,
for instance to the United States of America and other jurisdictions. As an example, where the service allows
for users to be located in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), their personal information is transferred to
countries outside of the EEA. We use standard contract clauses approved by the European Commission or other
suitable safeguard to permit data transfers from the EEA to other countries.
Standard contractual clauses
are commitments between companies transferring personal data, binding them to protect the privacy and
security of your data.
8.YOUR RIGHTS
We want you to be in control of your information, so we have provided you with the following tools:
Access / Update tools in the service. Tools and account settings that
help you to access, rectify or delete information that you provided to us and that's associated with
your account directly within the service.
If you have any question on those tools and settings,
please contact our customer care team for help here.
Device permissions. Mobile platforms have permission systems for
specific types of device data and notifications, such as phone book and location services as well
as push notifications.
You can change your settings on your device to either consent or oppose
the collection of the corresponding information or the display of the corresponding notifications.
Of course, if you do that, certain services may lose full functionality.
Deletion. You can delete your account by using the corresponding
functionality directly on the service.
We want you to be aware of your privacy rights. Here are a few key points to remember:
Reviewing your information. Applicable privacy laws may give you the right
to review the personal information we keep about you (depending on the jurisdiction, this may be called
right of access, right of portability or variations of those terms). You can request a copy of your
personal information by putting in such a request here.
Updating your information. If you believe that the information we hold
about you is inaccurate or that we are no longer entitled to use it and want to request its
rectification, deletion or object to its processing, please contact us here.
For your protection and the protection of all of our users, we may ask you to provide proof of identity
before we can answer the above requests.
Keep in mind, we may reject requests for certain reasons, including if the request is unlawful or if it
may infringe on trade secrets or intellectual property or the privacy of another user.
If you wish to
receive information relating to another user, such as a copy of any messages you received from him or
her through our service, the other user will have to contact our Privacy Officer to provide their
written consent before the information is released.
Also, we may not be able to accommodate certain requests to object to the processing of personal
information, notably where such requests would not allow us to provide our service to you anymore.
For instance, we cannot provide our service if we do not have your date of birth.
Uninstall. You can stop all information collection by an app by
uninstalling it using the standard uninstall process for your device.
If you uninstall the app
from your mobile device, the unique identifier associated with your device will continue to be
stored. If you re-install the application on the same mobile device, we will be able to
re-associate this identifier to your previous transactions and activities.
Accountability. In certain countries, including in the European Union,
you have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protection authority if you have
concerns about how we process your personal information. The data protection authority you can
lodge a complaint with notably may be that of your habitual residence, where you work or where
we are established.
9.RESIDENTS OF CALIFORNIA
If you are a California resident, you can request a notice disclosing the categories of personal
information about you that we have shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes
during the preceding calendar year. To request this notice, please submit your request
here. Please allow 30 days for a response. For your protection and
the protection of all of our users, we may ask you to provide proof of identity before we can
answer such a request.
10.HOW WE PROTECT YOUR INFORMATION
We work hard to protect you from unauthorized access to or alteration, disclosure or destruction of
your personal information.
As with all technology companies, although we take steps to secure your
information, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information will always
remain secure.
We regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and regularly review our
information collection, storage and processing practices to update our physical, technical and
organizational security measures.
We may suspend your use of all or part of the services without notice if we suspect or detect any
breach of security.
If you believe that your account or information is no longer secure, please
notify us immediately here.
11.HOW LONG WE RETAIN YOUR INFORMATION
We keep your personal information only as long as we need it for legitimate business purposes
(as laid out in Section 5) and as permitted by applicable law.
In practice, we delete or anonymize your information upon deletion of your account, unless:
we must keep it to comply with applicable law;
we must keep it to evidence our compliance with applicable law;
there is an outstanding issue, claim or dispute requiring us to keep the relevant information until it is resolved; or
the information must be kept for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud prevention
and enhancing users' safety and security. For example, information may need to be kept to prevent
a user who was banned for unsafe behavior or security incidents from opening a new account.
Keep in mind that even though our systems are designed to carry out data deletion processes
according to the above guidelines, we cannot promise that all data will be deleted within a specific
timeframe due to technical constraints.
12.CHILDREN'S PRIVACY
Our services are restricted to users who are 18 years of age or older.
We do not permit users under
the age of 18 on our platform and we do not knowingly collect personal information from anyone under
the age of 18.
If you suspect that a user is under the age of 18, please use the reporting mechanism
available through the service.
13.PRIVACY POLICY CHANGES
Because we're always looking for new and innovative ways to help you build meaningful connections,
this policy may change over time.
We will notify you before any material changes take effect so
that you have time to review the changes.
14.HOW TO CONTACT US
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, here's how you can reach us:
Online: here
By Post:
Privacy Officer
People Media, Inc.
8750 N. Central Expressway, Suite 1400
Dallas, TX 75231
Meet Single Women
Single women know this is the perfect place to meet eligible men. Women seeking like-minded single men are poised for success on PeopleMeet.com. Online dating has never been so easy.
It's free to browse. Click here!
Meet Single Men
Single men know this is the perfect place to meet single women. In the PeopleMeet community, online dating for singles is comfortable and simple. As a single man you will find great success with the premier online dating service.
It's free to browse. Click here!
DATING ARTICLES
Creating a Great Dating Profile on PeopleMeet.com
Creating a Great Dating Profile on PeopleMeet.com
See Less Articles
Copyright © 2020 People Media. All rights reserved.
32x1108.
